linkedin.com/in/hellotushaar

## **Experiences**

# Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer · 3rd Eye Visions

Full-time undergraduate student

July 2022 - October 2022

As an intern at 3rd Eye Visions, my role was to design user interface and user experience solutions for a variety of digital products. I was also responsible for the development of several web applications. Other roles and responsibilities include:

- To design and develop unique digital products.
- To maintain the products.
- · To collaborate with team members to build killer solutions.

#### Front-end Developer, Technical Support · Vibable Media

August 2019 - September 2020

Vibable Media is a digital marketing startup agency based in Dhaka, Bangladesh. My role was to create the agency's official website to showcase its services, accomplishment, and agenda to its potential customers. Other functions and responsibilities include:

- · Maintain the digital platforms and assets of the agency.
- Develop and deliver high-performing digital products.
- Assist non-technical members and employees in their tasks.

#### **Trainings & Certifications**

# Introduction to Hardware and Operating Systems · IBM Skills Network

June 2022 - Coursera

The course provided an introduction to the hardware and operating systems of a computer. It helped to understand the fundamentals of computer hardware, operating systems, and the relationship between the two.

## **Badges & Trophies**

# Microsoft Azure Fundamentals: Describe cloud concepts

September 2022 - Microsoft

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals is a learning path to help prepare for the AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals exam. This learning path helped me to get an exposure to cloud concepts and validate my knowledge and understanding of Azure services and its cloud concepts.

#### Introduction

Tushar is a self-taught tech fanatic with knowledge in front-end development and UI / UX design and invulnerable enthusiasm to keep improving at what he does. In the coming days, he sees himself as a cybersecurity expert to defend the digital life of billions.

#### **Portfolio Links**

→ https://github.com/hellotushaar

## **Expertise**

Frontend Development
UI / UX Design & Testing
Python Programming
Version Control System
Database Management

## **Technologies**

Python, Javascript, Git and GitHub, Linux, Figma, SASS, Google Workspace, HTML5, CSS3.

#### **Community Activities**

#### **CodeX Club · GITAM University**

August 2022 - Backend Lead & Technical Support

CodeX is a student-run club for coding and all things technology at GITAM University. As a core member of the club, I am responsible for holding events to help club members develop their web development skills. I am also responsible for handling projects related to the club.

## **CySec Club · GITAM University**

August 2022 - Member

CySec is a club that aims to help the students of GITAM University to learn about cybersecurity and to help to develop their skills in cybersecurity. As a member of the club,

- I build home labs to implement offensive security.
- · I learn with others about new tools and technologies.
- I collaborate with other members to help each other get better.

#### **Education**

## **Graduation · Bachelor's of Computer Applications**

2021 to 2024 · Gandhi Institute of Technology and Management, Bengaluru, India

As a student of BCA, I am learning computer science and software fundamentals from some of the most gifted and supportive professors at GITAM University. The program curriculum includes programming languages (Python, C++, Javascript, Java, R, PHP), information technology, data analysis, operating systems fundamentals, web technologies, data structures, data communication and networking, Unix programming, and many more. Additionally,

- I received the SII scholarship to pursue my undergraduate degree in India.
- Besides the core subjects mentioned above, I am encouraged to learn and engage with soft skills, club activities, venture development, sports, and many more.

#### **Higher Secondary School · Science**

Bangladesh Air Force Shaheen College, Chittagong, Bangladesh

Studied science subjects including Information Technology, Physics, Mathematics, Biology, and Chemistry.

#### Languages

English (Expert)

Bangla (Native)

Hindi (Conversational)

Spanish (Written)

#### **Hobbies**

Traveling, Blogging, Web Research.

#### **Contact Information**

Email: hellotushaar@gmail.com Website: www.hellotushaar.me

Linkedln: www.linkedin.com/in/hellotushaar GitHub: www.qithub.com/hellotushaar